This material is made available to you by Robbie half of the University of Melbourne
Of the copyright act 1968 it may be subject to copyright for more information visit the university
Copyright website
Ok
Good morning everybody
It's really useful
But if you have something to say
Please write a comment we really like hearing what you think of the course
Today was providing the background to understand
Brand is vulnerability called spectre
Today we're going to see that drawing on what you've already went
Before we do that
A couple of concerns people have had a couple of misconceptions first you don't need to know any assembly language
For this subject
A couple of weeks ago
I don't expect you to know the instructions for any particular
Machine
I would like to know the difference between the instruction set architecture
And micro-architecture which is
The lower level stuff which interprets those distraction
Second thing is something I've been saying about the project two didn't quite work
Face isn't going to be a second phase like that was the first projects
Is it going to be something or not
We're going to look at
You get a mark based on that goes marks won't be negotiable
We will however make sure
Ok
Of
Closely related
And some prices have multiple threads a threat is a sequence of executions
Within a process
Multiple threads in a process share a lot of resources
This also makes it easier for them to communicate
And work together as a team
We saw the notion of security contacts to the process
Liquor store
Parramatta privilege the processes to handle
Today we're going to be looking at his spectre itself
We shouldn't really be allowed to read it
Protection of memory
The basic technique
Is
Speculative execute code the real process of the wheel
Assembly language would never execute
And then this will cause some side effects
Are we observed that side effect
We look at ways we can do this why isn't causing this speculative execution either inside
Sandbox inside some supposedly safe environment
Berkeley packet filters
Implicitly this letter is revision of the past three lectures
If you find something that doesn't make sense
And probably other people will also benefit from
OK Google spectre is reading memory
Any given time there are lots of processes in memory
Is the kernel in memory processes
Processes is likely to be storing some sensitive information
Storing a key for an SSL session
Password manager
Random websites
From a user like bank account information or Bank
Password
All of this is
Very well protected by the way
You're not allowed to access that memory and put in
Roblox say you're not going to access memory
Bus
Around these blocks
Any processes address space
Not quite it has to be in the address space of a process that can influence
He doesn't have to be that process to run process
The execution of process
So as long as we can trick the process of forming a fairly generic sequence of operations
To see more details soon
Then we can access it's memory
We're going to focus on variant one which is violating bounds checking
All of you know or should know from somewhere
And then use that
Check
You know you should do that big if you don't do that you'll get a segmentation fault
Crash
So
The buffer
Location
To do
Memory
Orphan
Processes address space
Even if it's not part of that process
That the first one
Until this was standard practice
The address of the user
Why on earth would you do this
What the reason we do this is because the user will occasionally make a system call them
If you make it a write statement
Inside the library
To write
Is using a socket
Coles
Change
The address space space
All of the information get thrown out
Unfortunately I didn't have time to talk to you about translation
Remember this
Location
And so ugly every time
The address lookup
We don't want that
Taste version of the page table
Cases this mapping so the ball runs fast
Unchanged
Change process
We need a different page table
So if the clear
And that means every time we access ram
We need to do to access is slow
So to make Colonel faster
Ok we still need to change the program
We don't have permission to access
Every single process
Within multiple address spaces
The other example where the process address space contain David
Case
Something
Processes
In your browser unless you turn it off
JavaScript enabled
This means that
That's seriously dangerous strangers
Computer
It doesn't send it
Is very careful with
Sure when location is something that is supposed to be able to
Unless
We also stores
Destruction
Start off with fishing instruction
Conditional Grant conditional jump
It one of those
Next
It depends on
Awful
So we have to guess
This is called speculative execution
What we would do is look at this particular type of
Brunch
In this location
Normal evaluates to false
So would go ahead and executing the wood
What happens if
Well then we just make sure we don't actually write the results
Within the microarchitecture
We have buffers Witnesses with in the microwave
Find out
Whether or not
Tiring instructor
Retiring means put into bed finish it up
The buffers visible Isa registers
This is all good
Befriend
Before it actually a valid location or not
Good access
Exception
And I'm sure you all come across it every time you get it
When does it happen
Open Access
Because remember
The timer accessing it
Westpac
Will the code retires
Exception
Ok so only cause
Embarrassing I'm not allowed to read this beta
When are about to commit that to the real instruction set architecture
The problem is speculative execution
Instructions on never retired
Saying
Everybody thought this was safe
Architecture
Music
We have
Hardware remembers
So
Is no exception we think is not harm done unless something happens
Channel
Different meanings in different contexts
Communicating
It was never intended
Communication
Example of a side channel
Let me think
Ok you remember the time to live field in ip packet
Some people
Let's use the last bit of time to live field
Play some information
What's the time believe it or not
Sometimes with zero sometimes with the last bit being one
But the person receiving it gets this 30 than ones
Channel channel
Question
If you can't take it at all it can't use it
You can detect it
If you're looking for
Something like that
It's something you're looking for
Ben 10
Do you want to be
Sweet you can do this or not
And you can do that change anything
State
Second be later red
Stayed inside
The classic one
Is
The case
Only doing things
Alyssa review how page works
Bunch of memory big memory locations cold-case lines
Each of these are shown as being
About 4000 but the same principle applies
Paceline corresponds to
One region of memories anything anything
000 something
Is going to be stored in this
Case line
Eyes 90
Don't really matter anything with that bunch of exes
He's going to be put into this coastline
Remember that we can have multiple
Memory in line if we have both of them
So what do we do without inspector attack
Very natural code here which
Read the memory
To read
How do we expose that to the architecture
And
Another
Memory location
And this again we speak a little before
Because the pipelines can be quite long so we execute this as well
I was going to do it going to read
Different bass lines
Depending on the value of I
And to
Sending this to a level of
Executing
Two computers
Command
The Flash the case
Get rid of everything for whatever reason this is typically used changing contact
You're going from one process to another
Mathematical computations pilot test
See what happens happens
Base on that
I'm going to optimise my later accesses
This is a common thing to do and so clear in the case
Is not a constructor
But
And then run our instruction
Reading from space by x 4096
New island in line
One and only one case line
So what
It will read in data from this location
Bill reading data from this location
That's a long time
Really really quickly
You must have been in this one
I'm sorry can't tell which case line has been accessed
The last flight
Architectural significance
What was the location
Supposed to be able to read from
Sing
What is the spectre in saying we can use execution
Cause this
Operated
Up to newspaper instruction set architecture
I just checked everything
Yes that is most slow anyone with fast
And
That is essentially Spectra
What to do in memory
Do we normally can't read
Executing a coke and some memory
The read we can read
Resource is not something that is
Making out of a sandbox breaking out of the JavaScript Sandbox in particular
This
Again if index is less than the radar length
Then
Read
We do some manipulation here with x 4096
And in and with
Reading hour
Location
Do we actually do
Local John Nicholls
Why do we have this all with 0 why do we have this
The reason is
Self
Don't really do anything
Ring
Take it all with 0 nothing but we want to execute something
And this is
Spotify based on this read
Easy way of overcoming attack
Spectre paper
But to busy now
This is just say
Why does Germany
Time difference between
Make the dogs
Another can no longer do the case-based attack
From JavaScript
Unfortunately though
Do you need a precise clock
General solution
And just speak to can be used all sorts of other attacks
He's a particularly powerful one
Many user programs need to access packet streams amazing to writing a firewall freezer
Notify
Rules
Runs in space
Every single packet that comes through
Are we don't want
Change the office
Change
A little bit of packet filters
BCF
Designs
And essentially a little bit of a very supposedly very weak language but can't
That you want
This process
Stuff
Little compilot
Who sings
BCF is fine for the Hanley packets
Which is more powerful language used for
General interaction between kernel and and user is also used for handling things between
Queen
Machine
And in the process
Ok
The VM guests
Somebody to control what we do
Available to spectre speculative execution they say
Time
So you can
So from my IBM I can find out something about
Something else
How do you overcome that
What are the problems with Spectra not a software error
A bug you can just say well I'll change 51 that's where the problem is
Write down
Complete solution in software
To do anymore
Really really painful that is it a bit because
And also
Is quite slow
In the time of one ram access so we don't want to disable execution
So what Intel and AMD and arm have all done
Is offered firmware upgrade
Instructions
Put in these
Michael
Gumtree fixing up a little bit
Also add a new instructions
Forget everything
Yes
Because
Most of the time the Bouncing is true
Anything
So by Beyonce make a random guess it doesn't matter because
Getting information for through anyone there is much
Also
Anglican
I'm running
Different from when running
Instructions for that
And
The latest fixes are more fundamental that they're not just microcode
Actually changing
What is the next
Probably
Perfect
So what are the few things that have been done to try to make this less dangerous
Is the basic
Execution
Highway outside of
Where is supposed to be
Normally
Police code
What's the next higher power of two
And then say
I'm only going to consider a dresses that are end and
Going to rain a long way beyond
So you can read something
Maybe
But it's not
Something
More complex
It takes more time
Is another really beautiful approach called rich Berlin which is the return
Say function name brackets arguments
You need to do is take the program counter
Stored on the stack
You put onto the sack
Return
And returns
So when you
Return
Address
If you want to jump somewhere
Send
When you mess with the return address so that when you read instruction
Who is going to win
OK this is standard
Manipulate
Very efficient branch prediction techniques
Return to before popping off the sack because I remember there was a call
We doing that I'm making sure that when we speculatively return
Who is safe
A little bit leave it there but you never actually get to in terms of the Isa but
FaceTime
How to get to the sack
I'm putting this
And that again is a reasonably efficient way
Old combat
Aggressive approach
Is removing the kernel from every process address space
This is
What are we doing something that was relying very heavily on the CPU
Protecting
This is fine
Johnny game coming
If you're running a computer with a big drive
Computers
Do this every time
You go to
Go to the network
You need to do this context switch flashing the performance penalty
30%
Kinesics
Or not
Joe Bloggs
So he is probably say something
But speaker is just the start
Speaker is famous because it was the first of these type of attack
Micro architectural data sampling attacks
Ain't one of them
Is different
Has a different way of
Giving my critical state space
Different
Keep on coming every and every month or so there's a new one out
You guys are aware of the fundamentals and knowing if I applied
And respond appropriately
That's the end of all I have to say 10 minutes left
I'm more than happy to take questions answers about any aspect of the subject this lecture
That would be great if someone can think of something to ask
Question
Give me the
Ok I have much more complicated if statements essentially how far through does it
Question
It doesn't matter
How complicated the episode is
Jump
Remember a similar language to have
It has
Otherwise
Happens at the end
Big
Then it's important
So
Anything is
Another specifically at bounds checking
Amelia
Is very easy to find in somebody's code
Is that enough
That is hard to find so the people
And I found
A sequence
Become susceptible
So
How far is it
You just keep on speaker waiting until
Find out
Can you run out of internal storage to store all the Spectra results
But it can be certainly doesn't
It doesn't have to be later
Classroom
Any other questions
What is a few guys
Ok
Work out what people do and don't know
What Acacia line means
How many people understand how the timing attack on the couch works
How many people don't understand how the case works
Ok
Vacation
Memory
Here is very slow it's very big the case is right next to the CPU
Very fast but it's quite small
If you want to ring something from memory
Entire cake
Can we read
The Kate attack
Happens by clearing all of the stored in the case
And then doing 1 read from memory
1 readers controlled influenced by spectre
Go to ram
So because it will be very fast
Can we just before we did that every other nearby
Slowly got off to ram read it in
Ok and then return it to the process
The spectre attack his time how long does it take to read from this location
How long does it take for it from that location
How long does it take to reach from that location
Etcetera
One of the movie
By the the spectre gadget
Very slow
Doesn't make sense now that didn't understand it earlier
How many people still don't understand it
Would you like me to go through it again
What are you loading in originally
That's right
Will perform this command
It's saying access
This section memory bureau well spaced
Accesses
And he's going to depend on
Doesn't matter too much access that location is going to get whatever
And loaded into the cake
So next time you access space
1 x 10 x 4
Define
Populated with faces
Whangarei well space
So
Is
What is the address that we've been reading if we were the same address again
10 whiskeys
I'm in the attack again
Good question
Any other questions
Yes
Ok?
Coastline been accessed
What's next
So what
ND anything anywhere
Where the browser keeps it's passwords
If you know where it's keys if you know where
Beta
Expected you should be able to read
Young
Witches secret
Once you have the dater
Knowledge is power
If you switch around with them constantly would they get around this essentially yes
Location
Bus
Good question
Are you ok with the answer of what to do with the date 2 months ago
Yes
Before doing the attack clear the couch that's right
How busy instructions is clear the case
A user can clear the case
Iceland
And you don't know
How you should live in memory to give you the fastest possible access
So you might
As part of doing that experiment
Uses a given permission to create a case
Yes
Use a user
Process
Are you the process will say the case
And then do this attack
Centrelink know when the case is clear clear the case
People finding out another letterhead to
Questions
Hang out in front of the door for you to answer questions