This material is made available to you by Robbie half of the University of Melbourne
Of the copyright act 1968 it may be subject to copyright for more information visit the university
Copyright website
Ok for those two are watching the recording of the reason I'm not saying anything is because we're busy filling the
If you'd like to fill in the SES yourself while you're waiting for the recording to that starts
Go for it now otherwise you fast forward until I move slide off this one onto the next one
Just out of interest how many people are still feeling in the SES at the moment perfect I'll give you another file so minutes
OK how many people still feeling in the SES
That's perfect ok
Today is just revision with both dunhelen me before we revised
122 hours long
One Mark per minute
Three parts first multiple choice
What size should be 10?
7 and then 9
6 to 12 bucks no face
Will be covering material from both of the subject
Because the mid-semester test carrying some of the mark for it
I don't expect you to read this but those what is zoom in this is what the front page will look like this explained
Change the format of everything
Ok so first well I'm going to revise what we've done in the second half
Revise what was done in the first half
Ok the first thing we started off with was The Cure communications transport layer security
We looked at a cheese we looked a little bit of Howard achieve
Some bits of cryptography in their transport security
At the start
Will you negotiate the cryptography of the system going to be using throughout the rest of the
The section a little bit
But it's made look as it is so that makes it
We look at some of the nuts and bolts of
Symmetric vs asymmetric code example symmetric is the
Encryption standard
Will there be a couple of modes of operation and then we look at an asymmetric version
RSA and we saw how they can be used for authentication of signatures and the really important forward to
Yep good internet layer
A datagram service
All of the different properties that has
Quality of service what do we mean by quality of service
How to achieve quality of service why doesn't everybody have good quality of service
Typically include
Or the day to achieve for the packet loss rate any measure of
Performance
I will look at the fact the big part of the problem comes because the Internet is a shared network
To give you a good quality of service
Doesn't necessarily get paid any money for it and those cases we typically get just best effort
But within a company
You might
Be willing to pay for
Better quality of service
Contact mpls
Locate the predominant networking technology at the moment is ipv4
What constitutes an ipv4 packet
And we spent a lot of time looking at what is an ipv4 address
And there a lot of people who are confused about missing you have any lol
Please ask questions
The address is divided into a network address
First remit
And then the host network for the last few bits
How many humans
That specified by the subnet mask
Written notation
But we can't necessarily say that some of these digits some of the decimal digits
The network
Networking host is done
In the binary representation of this and that often appears in the middle of one of these
Blocks
We look at the factory this notion of something
Network address and host address
Limits to sizes networks
Samsung consequences
Network you belong to because any given that work can be submited further into long layers
Network
Hi can we also look at Network address translation for Network address and Port translation
It works it works by using one address on one side of the net box on a prime
I need a different address on the other side
And the fact that we have to
The number which we know which which
IP address
Real written onto it
Because I was running out of addresses
Are we saw that ipv6 is beginning to take hold and that has no shortage of addresses
But that is likely to say around
Because it has other benefits
As well as big disadvantages one clear benefit is
Security
Because that is about as well
But nice thing about Nat is it allows independent if you have an address from ISP on the other
Network speed to put a new appliance in
Ok we also look at packet fragmentation
Packets fragmentation happens when we send a packet is too big for one of the hops on the
What are the point to point links on the network
We can break down them
Ipv4
Ipv6
We can't
Fragmentation too much hassle the host to work out how big
Big teddy for that we need to have path-mtu-discovery
And that is also widely used in ipv4 even though fragmentation is in principle possible
Ok lol that's looking at things
Very general network
Problems to work out where
Send the packet
Rooting is the process of deciding that
Look up a table
And send the packet out
Which is
Working out what that table should be in the first place
Calculating the routing table
Can we look at static routing adaptive routing flooding which is very inefficient
But effective and we spend a bit of time on shortest path algorithm where we view the network as a
Labelled graph
What do I mean by label graph has a name each of the edges have a way
Wait on it and we can look at trying to find the path through this
Which minimises the sum of those egg weights
There is only really touched on dijkstra's algorithm I do understand
Turn headlights works and how to apply it
So he's a simple example of algorithm if we going from a to d
Open up
The neighbours of our
Open up the neighbours of a
Opening up memes
The cheapest of those
And then we say we're going to close it now and it's Neighbours
Ok and we stop when we get to the destination
Is the destination that's going to the shortest path to the destination
I take that back
As soon as we have closed the destination that's why we can stop
Ok shortest path algorithm typical used
Network within an autonomous system
Remember is that part of the network which is owned and run by a single entity
Don't have to worry about
Sharing information with themselves
But the internet is owned by a bunch of people
And each other
Anything about the internal networks
I don't want to tell anybody else
How my network is arranged
Soap bgp is the way routing between these entities don't trust
Which other
And it's a much more complicated
Range of
Effective and
The most important is who paid
So we have this arrangement where is your a small ISP you contract out your work too
Does the hard work for you and that means you pay with
Directions
The time in Australia the link between Australia and America
Power here
Valley free roofing means we saw the valley free routines that we don't tend to
Amaroo to go up
And then down again and then up again and then down would never have one of these low it's near AIS is
Advertising groups
Revenue for
You never tell someone to get somewhere through you unless you get a buck for doing it
And that means we never go up and down the advertised-routes 2 hour
Clients
Ok IP multicasting
It's ideal if you have an event that a lot of people are going to watch
Soccer streaming live conference
Call video
These are allocated a huge chunk of addresses call the class D addresses from the old class
System
And yes we can have lots of these groups
That's basically I need to say that
We spent quite a bit of time on medium access control the Mac sublayer
And we saw that we can have point-to-point links you plug in an ethernet cable that gives
Connection to another device you can have broadcast links you turn on your computer and the wife
Wi-Fi is talking to anyone who's in range and in the case of broadcast channels
How serious are my work carrier sense motorbikes it's carriers
Listen
You're welcome to transmit Alexis
We detect collisions
Very efficient approach
But we can't do that in wireless so we have to use csma-ca instead
Multiple access with collision avoidance
Good we didn't really talk much about full and half duplex enough
Ok ethernet
Ethernet is the most widely used protocol that is called a link layer protocol
Or network layer
The classic version would you see a CD was clearly a link layer protocol
Point to point
No relation
To ethernet
Clear timer we said that was the old this is the new we migrated from having a single wire running around
Having a hump we all have a wire connected to it and then without the computer
Switch
Smooth migration from the original to the switch version
It WiFi we looked at a little bit about
Wi-Fi standards we looked at the idea of having multiple channels
Wi-Fi devices can choose from
But we really only use 3 of them because the rest of them have parcel overlaps with bad for us
Is Messi a very slightly about 11 security
OK what are the other tasks of the link layer
The Middle cast
How to get data from one point
To a slightly different point one hop along the way you need to make sure that you can work out how to get
Frames
Put the boundaries of the frame to the wrong spot
It's responsible for making sure that any errors that happened in the physical layer of which there are very very
Don't make it up to the next layer
Baby pics of you along the way
And the fundamental role of the is flow control
This station is slow processing the data for some reason it needs to tell this other states
Listen to flow down it's ending not to send until the receiver has room store the new packet
Ok like the transport Layer 3 clear layers
Frequent flyer can work in you can have an acknowledged connectilis service
Would you like to acknowledge connectionless service
Can you ask them to tell you I received it
But it's just a nice way to pack it's not part of a sequence and then you can have an acknowledged connection-oriented
Service
Good
A beacon of the access points and
I'm here
Ok to talk about stuff
Operating systems
Attack
What is a pipeline
What does it mean when a pipeline stalls a pipeline you remember is when you have multiple
Jacksons been executed simultaneously
The hardware store
Information missing for the next one
Speculative execution
What you don't know for certain what the next instruction will be
But you start executing one anyway
Throughout the results or get to keep them
Even though assembly language is a very low level language
Still there's a language below that within the hardware which is microcode
The two basic
The basic memory techniques used by CPUs which is used for
And registers which news for current working
Female cat
Memory management more broadly we look at how you can have multiple programs sharing memory
In particular swapping and the first entire memory
Footprint of one process take it out putting the next one
Using paging
If you willing to break down some of the functions that makes
Is it the memory if anything it wants to virtual memory
Everything is in memory
558 needs as it needs it
New computer data is effective going through a string you don't need to
Really in the next memory location or not
Virtual memory the next part of a string is probably not in the next physical location of memory
Page
This is just contiguous memory
Perform This mapping using a page table
And the pace Abel says we're in memory eats actual location is
Which is what the program sees the memory is looking like
Ok all this operating system start stuff
To use is another aspect of the memory hierarchy which is case
Again we're getting the memory from is not
A copy a local copy which is very fast Traxxas
Level 2 level 3 and then we get virtual memory
Look at processes and threads
Most of the course were talking about processes we used to process was the endpoint
What actually is
He is a bunch of
Face got things like what is the memory the content of the memory
What is the process
A process for also have at least 13 of execution
Pets instructions being executed what happens next we have next
Execution can have multiple threads
And it has its own programs
Decode
We'll see look at the difference between
Different types of thread execution
Will use a code
Administrator or root code looked at the kernel
Increasing levels of priority
We need to switch from one to the other using system calls
Anytime you want to read data from a file read from the keyboard write to the network anything
Can't be done directly by user process has to be done by a system call to the kernel
The privileges to do that
Ok that's all there is on second half
Ok hello everyone
That's not good with the content
Can't
You don't have to
Pay attention to what I'm saying here
Expected to know what is the Protocol and the strengths and drawbacks of delivery model
That's how it is here and internet applications
We have already taqaza four types of application layer protocols the first one is
Http FTP SMTP DNS
Teacher notes how do they work and what are they and how
Communications between a fall for each of the following http
If you open the webpage then toward
What kind of Hep A TCP connections will be insulated and
How many of technicians are related to independence of the connection
And for FTP you are you Maori
Call Dad's each after command in the control connection how to how
Each commands work but then pulled up for loop commands are you
How many connections will be opened and how does that connect a connection
Work Pokemon
Hangouts 50 which is useful
Email then so you may let you know that's how I am where we wants to thank you email to
Baba how to process work samples in Perth to make a email and answer put in
SMTP server and how does email to push through the output to the
SMTP service of Bob and then I can pop get this email from the server
Power
Alice all you need to know dad's up the format of the email message
And then some also know that the common Ponds difference between SMTP
EPL
You made it you know that
Dingo camper white and what's the difference between between them and how
How is the DNS server require kit work
And the second part of the first place recommend you focus on that
Gold Coast beauty people
Call Nicole
Which is Channel 10 that's why it's not only useful
At transport layer you can be upright you use for any two layer that you may lead
And answer you evaluate your expert you understand how to apply this a principal tricky science
ADI Powder Coating for the application
Are pocket Mario sorry not notification and PCP
Streaming past TCP communication TCP flow control and TCP congestion control
Here
Press
Difference between transport layer protocol and and naturally a protocol
Understand that OK what's the main purpose and
Multiplexing and demultiplexing
You need to understand what you said ok and what
What is the soccer identifier indifference are protocol
And answer you need you also need to know that how does multiprocessing
Depressing work
A new tpu udp you may need to know that
Rocky and udp and customs you need to understand how to calculate GDP
That's all you need to know that I'm after utep
Alcohol sorry
Frankie are you also let you know how the day what is the process for sending a message over you
54 my Facebook
We have different type of article took over from Waurn Ponds
02350 and we also introduce various at 2:34
Problems at the deciding.
What what is the process for introducing the custom in the city and what is the first
Atka ganga Kata in the city
What what that's are the Wimpy sequence number used and why will it stop and wait for the mechanic Gumtree
Entity sign you may you may need to know
Oldest things and answer your us pet you'll be able to at the sides
Rtt in different scenarios
And a PS3 menu focus on three parts rtcp coming
Medication which is St Kilda Ponsonby a communication site
Believe that you are very clear about this how does steep the communicator work
TCP full control you need to know that what is the purpose of purple control what is
The paper idea info control define and of course you also let you know that
How does the typing window protocol in TCP full control work
And finally in congestion control of course you also let you know them
The purpose of congestion control and how does a
Congestion control Solstice Greek restaurants near the centre
Obsolete
Upside
App that centre perceived electrical just inside of stuff after sex
Commonwealth out of us which is what is the fastest smithing is and answer
Algorithms in PCB for controls livestock address
At all this tree algorithm follow independent
Direct better and collaborate to handle the TCP full control
Swap paint Bittersweet Chang with between each of the three algorithms here
You may need to know that I'm different you may need to understand ok
At this time stands out what if the size of the congestion windows
I'm here in the 1800 mi mi.
Secondment on our rent standard drop down 2221
And also you let you know that somehow
How does the algorithms watch that switch between each other for example when when are the fast
Switch transmission event happens what will the algorithm spirit and then they how
How is the ratio of the congestion Windows is updated
Ok that's in the First
Rick and answer in the Indus what week are we also
How far from consolidation town specification time is the same as the letter time in the email
DMT 6.23 and the NZ office of local intersection
Funky spex
The meeting room Gap the meeting room sorry
Easter
Ups
OK anyway I'm finally it so you are encouraged to do the FPS because you're free
Feedback is really important for us that can help us to improve our tea tree
I'm sorry if you suck you and if you have any questions you can ask
Yes
What is the address of sensitive information you say how does it find it
Not quite following the question you're saying is the truth security flaw the fact that you know where securedata is
The fact that you can use the address to look it up yes that is the true security flaw so
You can you can guess where secure data is stored but it's really hard big is a gigabyte
So unless you understand the code which you know it's looking
Speak to one help you much
By examining source code operating system then it sort of public fairly often where it stores things
Then you can read stuff you're not supposed to be able to read that's the real weakness a real strength inspector the real security weakness
After the lecture question
Yes
It's all relevant
It's not it's not a whole lot of time studying
The main reason for having waisake particular 2
For the second project so
It's important to note the basic ideas that exist and a useful and suchlike
Where do you click within the wireshark Windows 10 and such and such
Are the questions
Bgp doesn't advertise internal things yes
No no it doesn't advertise paid for them never ever Advertiser
Internal parts
Bgp is all about the next day
Compare how the ISS get the data from one end of themselves to the other end of themselves
That information is never never said
You never tell anybody else to pass through yourself all I know is
If you're connected to know Isa and ASB an essay is your customer
Daniel to tell ASB how to get to SA
Is that right
During customer I suppose you would because
That's actually getting paid for
Is it connected to your customer
You tell
How to get to a you tell everybody how to get away because you get paid for traffic goes to and from a
How to get to Beacon how to get to C
The other one through yourself
Because if you carry date of for them that you acting as a Transit ISP
You're not getting paid for that all so you wouldn't think they cost
The question
I beg your pardon
Can you read out the connections that would turn someone into a customer
Other questions
Question about part 1 questions about the structure of the exam questions about ideal study
Christian resources
Still got 10 minutes
10 minutes 149 by Mum watch
Computer ok with between 6 and 10 minutes question
Yes yes you need to actually email Eliza
40 Tales of the algorithm smoothie understand how they work
Yes
So like I said they no longer answer questions there's nothing we are expected to write a big chunk of code
Like I said what are the steps to setting up a socket
Respect that you would be able to tell us what system call is required for this so
Yes that sort of coding is assessable but you don't have to write a big a big thing to download a file or something
Just see for the subject
Yes
I will probably answer the letter just know what the basic things that need to be done
You need to do
I've got one other
Announcement / apology when I was reading through some of the things with things that I have been going to talk about
So I will upload a new version of this
Same thing as we didn't really cover the slides
So what was the example you gave
Creepy clock speed
That wasn't zone greatly in the lecture it was
Play more study more in the tutorial so yes I would expect that you would know the level of detail that was covered in the
Tutorial
That wireshark wireshark lab it was also something about
I think
That stuff is acceptable I won't be asking about killer but the actual networking
Contents
The final slides
Fine then
Nothing I said
Question
Nat and subnet
Very different is region of the address space
Been allocated to a network
So have a network master has more one Dixon it essentially
Matt is
Original
I'm not part of the network address is just one address that's too
Complete network
True of most of the material in those few lectures not really related at all
How many people would like a long explanation of how many people think they understand the difference between
Almond something
How many people think that I don't quite understand
Ok so
Nat is expanding
Address
Find a single address
Where is a network
State of address
3.0 binary tree
Going down is one of those trees
Pretend tree
Is actually a whole bunch of
It's like
Maps to whole network behind the portal
Answer the question
Annette
That is really a process translation so with that
Network has
Location
What's on the other side difference
Communicate with
So you can compete with the public Network at all but when you want to go
And that will do the translation of the address in the port and everything all look like a single Point
Does doing a lot of stuff
Inside we're just a whole lot of individuals
Time for half a question
Yes
Do you need to know any specific my crops no you don't you need to know the concept of
Realise
But different machines have different
Ok that's all the time for
Back and good luck